致法拉
"To Farrah,
愿你人生最大的谜题
may the greatest mysteries of your life
还有待揭开
lie ahead.
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle."
太感谢你了
Thank you so much.
我们机长也是你的大粉丝呢
You know, our pilot is also a huge fan.
可以也为她签个名吗
You think you could sign a book for her, too?
十分乐意  我只求她
I'd love to. All I ask in return is that
安全送我们到希思罗机场
she deliver us to Heathrow safely.
祝您在伦敦待得愉快  卡塞尔先生
Enjoy your stay in London, Mr. Castle.
谢谢
Thank you.
我被从指定的座位顶下来了
I got bumped out of my assigned seat.
你说你会想办法的
You said you'd fix it.
我说十分抱歉
I said you had my apology.
但这是头等舱唯一的座位了
This is the only seat available in first.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
我不知道他是谁  但我知道他是什么样的人
I don't know who he is, but I know what he is...
大混蛋
A giant ass.
爸爸  你什么时候开始这么紧张坐飞机了
Dad, when did you become such a nervous flier?
没有  我就是不喜欢气流
I'm not. I just don't like turbulence...
还有座舱压力骤降
Or sudden drop in cabin pressure
还有机械故障
or mechanical problems
还有坠机
or crashing.
不用担心
There's nothing to worry about.
就是气流有点不稳而已
It's just a little bumpy air. That's all it is.
气流就不该不稳
Air, by nature, should not be bumpy.
看看乘务员
Just look at the flight crew.
只要他们还在走动  还在微笑  就没事
If they're up and smiling, then everything is fine.
他们是还站着  但可没笑
Yes, well, they're up, but they are not exactly smiling.
爸爸  航程很长
Dad, it's a long flight.
你得把注意力转移到别的地方
You should really focus on something else,
否则感觉只会更漫长
or it'll seem even longer...
我们都会很难熬
for both of us.
好吧  我就不去理会死亡阴影了
Fine. I shall ignore the grim specter of death
只专注于我们的行程
and focus... focus on our itinerary.
好吧  车会去酒店接我们
All right. Car is going to pick us up from the hotel,
送我们去夏洛克·福尔摩斯协会
whisk us off to the Sherlock Holmes Society,
我将在那里跟各位推理作家同僚
where I will speak to my fellow mystery writers about...
其实  我今晚有计划
Actually, I made plans for tonight.
什么计划  跟谁啊
W-- what plans? With who?
几个在伦敦做交换学生的朋友
Oh, some friends who are doing their semester abroad in London.
我们要在南肯辛顿一家酒吧见面
We're meeting a pub in South Ken.
但夏洛克·福尔摩斯协会
But the, um, Sherlock Holmes Society
要在贝克街221号B集会啊
is convening at 221B Baker Street.
你不会想错过看夏洛克·福尔摩斯宅邸的机会吧
You don't want to miss the actual home of Sherlock Holmes.
你知道他是个虚构人物吧
You do know he's fictional, right?
但那地方是真的啊
Yes, but his address is real.
而且我还会讲话  如果你不在
And I will be speaking, and if you're not there,
-谁会为我骄傲啊  -我永远为你骄傲  爸爸
- who will be proud of me? - I'm always proud of you, dad.
但我都听过你演讲无数次了
But I've heard you speak a million times.
我知道你会说什么
I know what you're gonna say.
这可不可能
That is improbable.
你会说你不相信作者会遇到瓶颈
You'll say you don't believe in writer's block,
你写第一部小说是为泡一个妹子
that you wrote your first novel to impress a girl.
拜读大作家的作品能给你灵感
That reading great writers inspires you,
而跟他们一起饮酒
and drinking with them inspires you
会激励你在畅销书榜单上把他们比下去
to beat them on the best-seller list.
好吧
Okay.
显然我需要另找新的话题了
Clearly I need to develop some new material.
但这本来是
But this was supposed to be
传统的父女时光啊
old-fashioned father-daughter time.
爸爸  看着你对你的朋友发表讲话
Dad, watching you speak to your cronies
算不上是父女时光
isn't exactly father-daughter time.
而且我也不是12了
Besides, I'm not 12.
我们不用时刻在一起
We don't have to be attached at the hip.
好吧  死亡的阴影  又回来了
Okay. That impending specter of death... it's back.
贝克特  你怎么跑进去的
Beckett. How did you get in there?
通过神奇的无线网络
Through the magic of WiFi.
我就猜到你会在上网
I figured you'd be online.
我觉得你会想知道最新进展
So I thought that you would want an update.
我们破案了  是赛车手
We solved the case. The race car driver did it.
太好了
That's good to hear.
你那边没事吧
Is everything okay up there?
就是遇到了点气流
Just a little turbulence.
卡塞尔  有问题吗
Castle, is something wrong?
嗯  没事的
Yeah... everything's gonna be just fine.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
Castle?
只有我觉得这根本不叫"没事"吗
Is it just me, or does everything not seem just fine?
贝克特  放心
Beckett, relax.
就算气流再强烈  也不会把飞机搞下来
Even the most heinous turbulence won't bring a plane down.
而且每天有20趟航班飞离纽约
And every day, 20 flights leave New York
安全降落在伦敦
and land in London without a problem.
-卡塞尔的航班也不会有事  -是啊
- It's gonna be the same for Castle's flight, too. - Yeah.
没事的
It's gonna be all right.
各位  这里是机长艾德蒙斯
Folks, this is Captain Edmunds.
之前遭遇了气流
We hit some chop there,
但我们已经攀升至3.9万英尺高空
but we've climbed to 39,000 feet
到希思罗机场应该不会再有颠簸了
and expect a smooth ride all the way to Heathrow.
瞧  根本不用担心
See? There's nothing to worry about.
嗯
Yeah.
那他们怎么不笑呢
Now why aren't they smiling?
爸爸  你听到机长的话了
Dad, you heard the pilot.
我告诉你  不对劲
I'm telling you, something is not right.
我要去问个明白
And I am going to find out what.
打扰
Excuse me.
先生  安全带警告灯还开着呢
Sir, the seat belt sign is still illuminated.
请回到你的座位上
If you could please return to your seat...
你没笑  你们都没笑
You're not smiling. None of you are smiling.
机长也在这里  怎么回事啊
And the captain's here? What's going on?
出什么机械故障了吗
Is there some kind of mechanical problem?
-先生  请回去...  -吉姆  等等
- Please, sir, just return... - Jim, wait. Um...
或许他能帮上忙
Maybe he can help.
卡塞尔先生  我是艾德蒙斯机长
Mr. Castle, I'm Captain Edmunds.
你跟纽约警局合作  是吗
You work with the N.Y.P.D., right?
我们需要你的协助
We could actually use your assistance.
协助什么
My assistance with what?
这是凯尔·福特
This is Kyle Ford.
他是本航班的空警
He's the air marshal on this flight.
我见过他  他就坐在我那排
I saw this guy. He's sitting in my row.
至少  刚刚还在的
He... at least, he was sitting in my row.
这跟空警有什么关系
What does this have to do with the air marshal?
一小时前  他向地面办事处发了短信
An hour ago, he sent a text to his field office
称本机上有安全隐患
about a security issue onboard this air craft.
什么样的安全隐患
What kind of security issue?
"大洋航空57号航班可能面临威胁
"Possible threat to Oceanic Air flight 57.
正在调查"
I'm investigating."
福特的短信里只说了这么多
That's all Ford said in his text.
他跟你怎么说的
And what did he tell you?
可惜的是  我没能跟他说上话
Unfortunately, I haven't been able to talk to him.
福特先生失踪了
Mr. Ford is missing.
失踪
Missing?
失踪了
怎么可能  你们搜飞机了吗
How could he be missing? Did you search the plane?
从头至尾
From front to back.
鉴于目前状况  我已接到命令
Given the circumstances, I've been instructed
把我自己锁进驾驶舱继续飞往希思罗机场
to lock myself in the cockpit and continue on to Heathrow.
-恐怖主义应对机制  -没错
- Terrorism protocol. - Precisely.
现在  空警行踪不明
Right now, with the air marshal unaccounted for,
你是飞机上
you're the closest thing we have
最接近执法人员的人了
to law enforcement on this plane.
光这一点就够令人担忧了
Which in itself is cause for concern.
你愿意帮助我们吗  卡塞尔先生
Will you help us, Mr. Castle?
当然  我当然愿意
Yeah. Yes. No, of course.
当然  好吧
Of course. Okay, um...
你们搜查飞机时  都检查了哪些地方
When you searched the plane, where did you look?
-卫生间  厨房  -好的
- Um, the restrooms, the galleys. - Good.
-还有行李舱  -很好
- Uh, cargo hold. - Great.
包括行李架都检查了
Even the overhead bins.
可以确定福特先生在飞机上的某处
Okay, well, Mr. Ford is on the plane somewhere.
我们只能再检查一次了
We just have to search again.
也许  这次还是别检查行李架了
Maybe... skip the overhead bins this time.
真不明白  就好像他凭空失踪了
I don't know. It's like he just disappeared.
根本讲不通啊  借过
It doesn't make sense. Excuse me.
你了解那位空警吗
How well do you know the air marshal?
不太了解
Not that well.
福特先生一个月就跟我们飞两次
Mr. Ford only flies with us like twice a month.
他很专业  讲礼貌  这里
He's very professional, very polite. There you go.
好的  这里
Okay. This...
是唯一一处
Is the only other place
我们还没进行二次搜索的地方
we haven't given a second look.
福特知道怎么下来吗
Does Ford know how to get down here?
当然  他和我们一样也能进入所有区域
Of course. He has access to the entire plane, just like we do.
和机身等长  所有地方都找过了吗
Runs the length of the plane. And you looked everywhere?
我们并没有把所有行李取出来
Well, we didn't pull out all the luggage
因为当时并没有发现下面有人
'cause there was no sign anyone was down here.
这倒霉的飞机上有条蛇哎
There's a snake on the mother-flyin' plane.
没遇上上周随机运送的斗牛犬
You're lucky it wasn't the pit bulls
算你走运了
we had to ship last week.
看看这个行李
Look at this luggage.
什么时候允许衣物
Since when does the airline allow
露在行李箱外面了
clothes hanging out of bags?
一般不允许的
They don't, not usually.
三个不同的行李箱
That's three different bags...
分别属于三位乘客
from three different passengers.
这没道理
That doesn't make any sense.
-除非  -除非什么
- Unless... - Unless what?
除非是有人把另一个箱子的东西取了出来
Unless someone took the clothes out of another suitcase,
塞进了这三个箱子里
stuffed them into those three bags.
你不会是认为
You don't think...
只有打开看看才知道了
One way to find out.
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
那是福特空警
That's air marshal Ford.
不会吧  空警死了
You've got to be kidding me. The air marshal is dead?
不仅死了  而且头部遭受重击  被杀
Not just dead, but bonked on the head, murdered.
而且还有呢
And there's more.
还有
There's more?
凯尔·福特的枪套是空的  枪不见了
Kyle Ford's holster is empty. His gun is missing.
好吧  那么可以认定凶手持有武器
Okay, so, uh, we have to assume that the killer is armed.
而且他们可能还有下一步计划
And they may have another agenda --
挟持人质  劫持飞机
taking hostages, hijacking the plane.
说清楚  这绝非我要的轻松伦敦之旅
F.Y.I., this is not the relaxing London getaway I had planned.
这事还有谁知道
So who else knows about this?
机组人员  空警
Well, just the flight crew, the air marshal service,
还有联调局
and the F.B.I.
我能帮什么忙
And how can I help?
他们给了我一份乘客名单
Uh, they gave me a copy of the flight manifest.
我邮件给你了  现在应该到了
I e-mailed it to you. You should have that by now.
好的  我会和联调局合作
Good. I'll coordinate with the F.B.I.
开始查找有不良记录的乘客
And start running names to look for red flags.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
阿丽克西斯也在航班上
Alex is on this flight,
还有其他近两百名乘客
along with almost 200 other people.
卡塞尔  你能做到的
Castle... you can do this.
做到什么  我该做什么  抓凶手吗
Do what? What am I supposed to do, catch the killer?
凶手可能是任何人  都不知道从哪下手
It could be anyone. I wouldn't know where to start.
从头开始
You start at the beginning.
建立死者的时间线
We build a timeline for our victim,
和以往的第一步一样
same first step we always take.
是啊
Right.
只是  这次  这第一步是
I just -- this time, that first step is...
在一万两千米的高空上
39,000 feet off the ground.
卡塞尔  我会陪着你
Castle, I'm gonna be here with you.
在地上想办法破这个案子
I'll be working this case from the ground,
和大家一起
along with the boys.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
我能破案的
I can figure this out.
我知道
I know you can.
抱歉  小姐  这里乘客不能进入
I am sorry, miss. This area is off-limits.
她是和我一起的
Oh, she's -- that's -- she's with me.
她是我女儿  她是...
That's my daughter, and she's...
你走了好久  我很担心
You were gone so long, I got worried.
你在这儿干什么呢
Why are you down here?
我待会儿打给你  爱你
Uh, I'll call you later. I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
一直喜欢歪心狼
Always rooting for that Coyote,
-不喜欢BB鸟  -就是
- not the Road Runner. - Right.
两位
Guys?
我需要你们的帮助
I need your help.
你觉得可能是谁干的
Who do you think could have done it?
这正是我想解决的问题
Well, that's what I'm gonna try to figure out.
怎么做
How?
和机组人员一起重现福特的行动
By reconstructing Ford's movements with the flight crew.
同时  我需要你不要声张
In the meantime, I need you to keep this to yourself
回上面安全的机舱去
and go back upstairs where it's safer.
那儿就安全吗  凶手不是在那儿吗
How is it safer? Isn't that where the killer is?
我只是不想让你卷进来
Look, I just don't want you to be a part of this.
我已经卷进来了  我能帮忙的  爸爸
I'm already part of it. I can help, dad.
我还当过蕾妮的实习生呢  记得吗
I interned with Lanie, remember?
我可以检查尸体找线索
I'll check the body for clues.
阿丽克西斯
Well, A-Alexis --
这飞机上有个杀人犯
There's a killer on this plane.
我们还不知道他是谁  想干什么
We don't know what he's planning or who he is,
也许我能帮上忙呢
and maybe I can do something about that.
我不会回座位的
I am not going back to my seat.
哪怕意味着我们要时刻在一起吗
Even if it means us being joined at the hip?
真的假的啊
Really?
这种时候你还拿这话还击我
You're throwing that back at me now?
无话可说了吧
Right in your face.
我开始检查了
I'll get started here.
你去跟机组人员合作
You go talk to the flight crew
-想办法找到凶手  -好的
- and try to figure out who did this. - Right.
凶手就在外面
It was someone out there.
这些人中的一个杀害了凯尔·福特
One of those people killed Kyle Ford.
我刚刚告诉了其他空乘
I just told the other flight attendants.
我还是不敢相信
I still can't believe this.
现在怎么办  卡塞尔先生
What do we do now, Mr. Castle?
现在我们想办法拼凑出
Well, now we try to piece together
被害者死前在哪里  和谁说过话
where the victim was and who he had contact with before he died.
你们最后一次看到福特空警
When was the last time anyone remembers
是什么时间
seeing air Marshal Ford?
-谁在酒水服务时招待的他  -是我
- Wait, who served him during drink service? - I did.
这是早上八点半的航班
Okay, this was an 8:30 AM flight.
酒水服务时什么时候
Drink service occurred when?
是十点钟开始的
Uh, we start at 10:00.
等我回收垃圾的时候
And by the time I did the trash pickup,
福特就不在他的位子上了  不见了
Ford wasn't in his seat. He was gone.
没有不见  我在用餐时间看到他了
Not gone. I noticed him during meal service
-在靠近机尾的地方  -他在做什么
- near the back of the plane. - Doing what?
我没看到  一位乘客缠住了我
Oh, I didn't see because a passenger got in my face
抱怨食物很糟糕
about the lousy food.
我们最近为了省钱改了供应商...
We recently switched vendors to save money --
我...你什么时候看到他的
I -- when you saw him,
他是在第一过道还是第二过道
was he in aisle 1 or aisle 2?
如果是用餐时间的话
If it was meal service,
过道一是被餐车堵住的...
aisle 1 is blocked by the cart --
那就是第二过道  什么时间呢
So aisle 2. What time was that?
快到十一点的时候
Just before 11:00.
我们是在11:35的时候发现尸体的
And we found the body at 11:35,
这样在他被杀之前有个约35分钟的空当
giving us about a 35-minute window before he was killed.
还有其他人看到他在飞机尾部了吗
Does anyone else remember seeing him at the back of the plane?
他有和其他人一起吗
Was he with someone?
加油  伙计们  努力想
Come on, you guys, try to remember.
也许可以问坐在后面的乘客有没有看到他
Maybe we can ask the passengers in back if they saw him.
不行  如果这样做了
No, if we did that,
乘客们就会知道有什么不对劲了
word would get out something is wrong,
说不定凶手也就知道了
Word that could make it back to the killer.
也许还有其他的办法
Maybe there's another way
能知道福特在过道后部做什么
To know what Ford was doing at the back of this aisle.
那两位先生这样自拍了多久了
How long have those two gentlemen been taking selfies?
度蜜月的那对
The honeymooners?
喝完第一杯酒就开始了  他们很有爱
Since their first Pimm's cup. They're adorable.
我得和他们聊聊
I have to talk to them.
我们要做什么
What should we do?
你们的任务最艰巨了
You have the hardest job of all.
假装什么事都没有发生
Pretend like everything's normal.
我觉得接下来的旅程
I think for the rest of the trip
我们都应该像这样说话
we should talk like this.
真是优雅
So posh.
英音的"自拍"怎么说
How do you say "selfie" in British?
自帕
Sew-fee!
像索菲似的
Sophie?
要不我来帮你们俩好好拍一张吧
Why don't I grab a proper picture of the two of you?
-太好了  谢谢  -没问题
- Oh, great, thanks. - You bet.
准备好
Here we go.
能快点吗  我都快笑僵了
Can you hurry up? My face is hurting.
好了  再来一张
Right. One more for safety.
好的
Okay.
你俩是怎么认识的
So how did you guys meet?
那可是很长的故事
It's kind of a long story.
我最喜欢听长故事了
I love long stories.
我的天
Oh, god...
你要处理这种事真是糟糕  亲爱的
It's awful what you're dealing with, sweetie.
非常感谢你的帮忙  蕾妮
Thanks for your help, Lanie.
客气什么  我真希望还能帮上更多的忙
Are you kidding? I just wish there was more I could do.
我会指导你一步步做的  放心
I'm gonna talk you through this, all right?
你想先看看头部的伤口吗
Do you want to see the head wound first?
好的  不过你得凑得非常近才行
Yeah, but you're gonna need to get in really close.
试试把头发往后面拨一点
Try moving the hair back a little.
这样就好了
Yeah, there we go.
你能看出他是被什么击中的吗
Can you tell what he was hit with?
很难说  一个长条形的  比如管子
Mm, it's hard to say. Something oblong. A pipe, maybe.
我的天
Oh, man.
阿丽克西斯你还好吗
Alexis, are you all right?
只不过是一具尸体罢了
It's just another body.
你之前经历过很多次了
You've done this plenty of times before.
我不是因为这个尸体而难受
It's not the body I'm worried about.
是那个杀了他还偷走他的枪的人
It's the person who killed him and took his gun.
看了这个伤口  关于凶手
And looking at this, there is something
我能说出点有用的东西了
I can tell you about who that person is.
爸爸...
Dad...
蕾妮发现了什么吗
Lanie find something?
没有搏斗的迹象  看上去像是
No sign of a struggle, but it looks like
福特因脑后遭到一记重击而死...
Ford died from a single blow to the back of the head --
伤口在左侧颅顶骨
The left parietal bone.
那凶手一定是突然袭击他的
So the killer must have caught him by surprise.
更重要的消息是根据伤口的角度来看
The bigger news is that the angle of the blow
凶手是个左撇子
indicates that whoever did this was left-handed.
从统计学的角度来说  这样就排除了
Statistically speaking, that rules out
飞机上的大部分人  干得好
most everyone on the plane. Good work.
那对同性恋夫夫  他们是嫌犯
The...gay couple? Are they suspects?
不  应该不是他们
Nah, I really doubt it.
那你怎么会有他们的自拍照
Then why do you have their selfies?
我把照片从他们手机上电邮了过来
Well, I e-mailed them to myself off their phone.
说来话长
It's a long story.
都快和他们如何相识的故事一样长了
Almost as long as the one about how they met.
但他们拍照的时候
But they take these near the time
正好是空警福特在机尾的那段时间
Air Marshal Ford was at the back of the plane.
我希望他会和凶手一起
I was hoping he'd show up in one of them
出现在某张照片里  可惜不走运
along with the killer, but no luck.
视频里也没有吗
Not even in the video?
我还没来得及看这个呢
Actually, I didn't check out that one.
大家好
Hello!
我们结婚了
We did it!
看后面  他就在那里
In the background. There he is.
那是福特
That's Ford.
不过他是一个人
But he's not with anybody.
他在查看顶部行李箱
He was checking the overhead bin.
不过在找什么呢  不是他的包
Yeah, but for what? Not his own bag.
他是和我们一起在头等舱的
He was up here in first with us.
再播放一遍
Let's play it again.
说不定里面有什么
Maybe something's in there.
福特说他在调查一个可能的威胁
Ford says he was onto a possible threat.
不过他根本没在往里面看
But he's not even looking inside.
因为那个行李架就是个幌子
Because the overhead bin is a ruse.
你看福特一直在略过肩膀看别的地方
See how Ford is glancing over his shoulder?
-他在观察什么人  -你说得对
- He's clocking someone. - You're right.
是这家伙
It's this guy, uh...
26B
26B.
看
And look.
他发现福特在看他了
He realizes Ford is watching him.
26B  26B...
26B, 26B...
伊萨多·巴尔顿
Isadore Baldon.
伊萨多·巴尔顿  25岁  来自布鲁克林
Isadore Baldon, 25, of Brooklyn.
没有犯罪记录  但是...
No criminal record, but...
有麻烦了  卡塞尔
We have a problem, Castle.
什么样的麻烦
What's the problem?
他和你描述的那个人不一样
He doesn't match the man that you described.
我们联系上了巴尔顿  他还在市里呢
We contacted Baldon. He's actually here in town.
他的护照好几周之前被偷了
His passport was stolen weeks ago.
坐在26B的那个人  绝对不是伊萨多·巴尔顿
Whoever is sitting in 26B, it's not Isadore Baldon.
也许这就是福特一直留意他的原因
Oh, maybe that's why Ford was watching him.
他发现了他偷护照
He got onto that somehow.
不久之后福特就被杀了
And then moments later Ford was murdered.
我想我们找到凶手了
I think we found our killer.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
大汗淋漓  他很紧张
Sweating bullets. He's nervous.
他当然很紧张  他杀了凯尔·福特
Of course he's nervous. He just killed Kyle Ford.
还不能确定  吉姆
We don't know that, Jim.
他用偷来的护照坐飞机
He's flying on a stolen passport.
还要求坐在靠近行李舱的后排
He requested a seat in the back near the cargo hold.
你们看过视频了
You saw the video.
福特当时在监视他  现在却死了
Ford was watching him, and now he's dead.
黛比  你难道不认为
Debbie, you can't tell me he doesn't meet the criteria
他对乘客和机组人员构成威胁了吗
for posing a threat to passengers and crew.
不  他当然是威胁  在这种情况下
No, he definitely does. Under the circumstances,
我们有权拘捕他
we're empowered to detain him,
而且我们受过这种训练
and we have the training to do so.
我觉得你们不该这么做  现在还不行
I don't think you should, not just yet.
你不需要对飞机上的人负责
Well, you're not responsible for the people on this plane.
但我们需要
We are.
是的  而且如果是他的话  他可是有枪的
Yeah. And if he did it, he has a gun.
而我  不想等到他开枪再去拦他
And I, for one, don't want to wait for him to start shooting it.
可如果他不是我们要找的人怎么办
And what if he's not our guy?
你去把他拿下
You go out there and take him down,
人们会开始惊慌  真正的凶手就警觉了
It'll start a panic, alert the real killer,
那他可能还是会开枪
and he may pull a gun anyway.
好吧  那你有什么提议
Okay, so what do you propose?
我们要确认他的身份
We need to identify him,
搞明白我们对付的人是谁
figure out who it is we're dealing with.
是不是又要送饮料了
Isn't it about time for another drink service?
本该是的  可是航空公司削减预算
It would be, except for that the airline's cut back,
-所以我们只能...  -吉姆  吉姆
- so now we're only allowed... - Jim. Jim.
我付钱
My treat.
有垃圾吗
Trash?
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
要我收走吗  先生
Can I take that for you, sir?
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
做得好  法拉
Well played, Farrah.
现在怎么做
What are we doing now?
他用自动铅笔的铅粉充当取指纹粉末
He's using the graphite from his mechanical pencil to make fingerprint powder.
我在《百战天龙》里看过
I saw this on "MacGyver" once.
我还见过李察·狄恩·安德森[主演]
Well, I actually met Richard Dean Anderson.
-你知道他说什么吗  -能先干正事吗
- You know what he said? - Can you please do it already?
-说得对  -谢谢
- Right. - Thank you.
真的有用
It's actually working.
太好了
Sweet.
我在联调局的数据库里找到了匹配
I got a hit off the f.B.I. database.
-艾曼·哈达德  -他是叙利亚人
- Aiman Haddad. - He's a Syrian national in the U.S.
凭学生签证来到美国  就读于哈德逊大学
on a student visa, enrolled at Hudson University.
24岁
24 years old.
等一下  如果他是合法入境  那为什么
Wait, if he's here legally, then why would he be
要用偷来的护照坐飞机呢
traveling on a stolen passport?
可能是因为联调局把他列在了禁飞名单上
It might be because the f.B.I. has him on the no-fly list.
什么原因
For what reason?
显然艾曼·哈达德跟伊斯兰国有关
Apparently Aiman Haddad is affiliated with I.S.I.S.
他是恐怖分子吗
He's a terrorist?
还有更糟的  我跟哈达德哈德逊大学的室友谈过
It gets worse. I just talked to Haddad's roommate at Hudson.
他说哈达德最近对宗教非常痴迷
He said that Haddad had recently become super religious
而且把他的东西全都卖了  室友问他为什么
and sold all of his stuff, and when the roommate asked why,
哈达德说他不再需要这些东西了
Haddad said that he wasn't going to be needing it anymore.
我们得告诉卡塞尔
We got to tell Castle.
好的  谢谢你告诉我
Yeah. Thank you for letting me know.
我一会儿再打给你
I'll call you later.
怎么了  贝克特怎么说
What is it? What did Beckett say?
你回到头等舱去
I want you to go back to first class.
在那儿等着我去找你
Stay there until I tell you.
好的
Okay.
-小心点  老爸  -好的
- Be careful, dad. - Okay.
这么说他是坏人了
I take it he's a bad guy.
他在禁飞名单上  而且禁飞的理由很充足
He's on the no-fly list, and for good reason.
-这么说他是恐怖分子  -天哪
- So he's a terrorist. - Oh, my God.
他杀死了空警
He murdered the air marshal.
能够做出这么大胆的行为
Now that is a bold act committed by someone
说明他已经不在乎飞机降落后自己会被抓
not concerned with what happens to him once the plane lands.
因为这架飞机可能根本不会降落
Because maybe the plane won't be landing.
我觉得我们可以做最坏的打算
I think we can assume the worst.
假设他的计划不仅是杀死凯尔·福特
Assume that his plan is bigger than killing Kyle Ford.
好的  我们知道该怎么做
Okay, we know what to do.
首先  要尽可能把他隔离开
First, we isolate him if possible.
我会控制住他的双手  这样他就不能拿枪了
I'll control his hands so he doesn't go for the gun
或者其它危险品
or something worse.
我去拿束线带把他捆住
I'll get the zip ties to secure him.
很好  你们也说了  我们得悄悄地做这些
Good, and like you said, I think we should do this quietly.
想办法让他离开座位
Try to get him out of his seat
并且远离其他乘客
and away from the other passengers.
我可以广播让他到飞机后部的厨房
I could page him back to the rear galley.
他可能会起疑心  这样太冒险了
He might get suspicious. That's too risky.
如果他意识到我们要控制住他
If he realizes we're trying to take him down,
他可能会狗急跳墙
he may do something desperate.
你在干什么啊
Hey, what are you doing?
怎么了
What's going on?
把门打开
Open the door!
你能听懂他在说什么吗
Can you understand what he's saying?
是谁  你在跟谁通话
Who is that? Who are you talking to?
你说了什么
What were you saying?!
他说了什么
What was he saying?
他说"他们知道了  很快一切就会结束"
He said, "They know, and it'll all be over soon."
贝克特  我刚跟国土安全部通过电话
Yo, Beckett, I just got off with homeland security.
哈达德拨的那个电话号码
The number that Haddad was calling
是叙利亚的一部手机
was traced to his Syrian mobile account.
卡塞尔  你听见了吗
Castle, did you hear that?
是的  知道他是打给谁了吗
Yeah. Do we know who he was calling?
不知道  国务院正在跟
No. State's trying to coordinate
叙利亚政府协商  不过他们
with the Syrian government, but they're not expecting
一般不会配合
any kind of cooperation.
你们搞错了
You are making a mistake!
我有权利
I have rights!
我们检查了他的座位
Okay, we checked his seat
还有他的行李  没有发现枪
and his carry-on, and there's no sign of a gun.
贝克特  找不到枪
Beckett, we can't find the gun.
他可能藏在什么地方了
Well, he might have hidden it somewhere.
或者他在飞机上还有同伙
Or he has a partner who is onboard.
无论如何  卡塞尔  你都要审讯他
Either way, Castle, you're gonna have to interrogate him.
我
Me?
你都跟我一起审讯过上百次了
You've been with me in hundreds of interrogations.
是的  可那时并没有关系到我的生命
Yeah, just never when my life depended on it,
或者其他人的生命
along with everyone else's.
各位  我还有坏消息
Hey, guys, I have more bad news.
航空公司说
According to the airline,
哈达德还带了一个经过检查的包上了飞机
Haddad has a checked bag on the flight.
联调局希望你们能找到  并搜查一下
F.B.I. needs you to locate and search it.
真好  那要是发现什么呢
Great. And if we find something?
如果是爆炸装置
In the event there's an explosive device,
拆弹组会告诉你怎么做的
the bomb squad will talk you through it.
我们要找到他的行李
We need to find his luggage.
-我跟你去找  -不不  你和法拉
- I'll go with you. - No, no, no. I need you and Farrah
到上面去让大家保持冷静
upstairs keeping things calm.
很多乘客在询问情况
The passengers are starting to ask questions.
你怎么跟他们说的
What did you tell them?
一位男士喝了太多的酒
That a gentleman had too much to drink,
不过我不确定他们是否相信
but I'm not sure they believed me.
我去  越快找到  我们就越安全
I'll go. The faster we find it, the safer we'll be.
好了
All right.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
不用靠运气  你已经做了无数次了
You don't need it. You've done this a million times.
有发现就告诉你
I'll let you know if I find anything.
拜托  这完全是个可怕的误会
Please. This is all a terrible mistake.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
伊萨多·巴尔顿
Isadore Baldon.
也许应该重来一遍
Maybe we should try this again.
我们知道你是艾曼·哈达德
We know you are Aiman Haddad
而且你和伊斯兰国有密切联系
and that you have ties with I.S.I.S.
你的计划是什么  谁是你的同伙
Now what is your plan, and who are you working with?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
"他们知道了  很快一切就会结束"
"They know, and it'll all be over soon."
那是你刚才在手机上说的话
That's what you said upstairs on the phone.
你在跟谁通话
So who were you talking to?
既然你不会相信我
Why should I answer
我为什么还要回答你
when I can see you won't believe me?
从这进去
Through here.
类似事件以前发生过吗
Anything like this ever happen on a flight before?
我经历的最接近的一次是
Closest I came was a 90-year-old
一位90岁的老人犯心脏病
who had a heart attack.
幸运的是  那次事故结局很圆满
Luckily, that one had a happy ending.
-这次也会的  -是吗
- This one will, too. - Yeah?
你做这行多久了
How long have you been doing this?
30年  还以为已经见过所有的...
30 years. Thought I'd seen it all --
每一个疯狂的乘客  每一个国家
Every crazy passenger, every country.
却遇上了这事
Now this.
如果有人能解决此事  非我爸爸莫属
If anyone can figure it out, my dad can.
真庆幸他在这趟航班上
Good thing he's on this flight.
你有这样的家庭真幸运
You're lucky to have family like that.
是的  是很幸运
Yeah. I guess I am.
你呢  有孩子吗
What about you? You have kids?
该怎么说呢  我总是在天上飞
Ah, what can I say? I was always up in the air.
找到了  伊萨多·巴尔顿  这是他的包
Got it. Isadore Baldon. This is his bag.
我不是警察  也不是空警
Now, I'm not a cop, and I'm not an air marshal,
但我会搞清楚你在图谋些什么
but I'm gonna find out what you're up to.
你知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
因为我女儿在这架飞机上
Because my daughter is on this plane,
我不会让任何意外发生在她身上的
and I'm not going to let anything happen to her.
我不是恐怖分子
I am not a terrorist.
禁飞名单上有你的名字
You're on the no-fly list.
都是因为我那该死的表兄决定加入伊斯兰国
Only because my idiot cousin decided to join I.S.I.S.
你用偷来的护照上的飞机
You're flying on a stolen passport.
用真名我没法出行
I couldn't travel under my own name,
除此之外我还能怎么办
so how else should I fly?
为什么那么着急要坐飞机呢
Why the sudden urgency to fly in the first place?
我必须回叙利亚
I need to go back to Syria.
为什么  你的任务是什么
Why? What's your mission?
什么任务
My mission?
我必须回家
I have to go home.
我母亲病得很重  胰腺癌
My mother is very sick. Pancreatic cancer.
我向运输安全管理局作出申请
I petitioned the T.S.A.
我尝试了正规途径
I went through the proper channels.
但现在她只有几周的生命了
But now she only has a few weeks to live.
我在电话里就是跟她在讲话
She is the one I was talking to on the phone.
解释一下这个
Explain this.
那个空警一直盯着你
See how the air marshal is staring right at you?
他是空警吗
He's the air marshal?
他看出我很紧张  是不是
He saw I was nervous, didn't he?
就是因为他我才被扣留的吗
Is he the reason I'm being detained?
是的  可以这样说
Yeah, you might say that.
他发现你图谋不轨
He realized you were up to something,
所以你跟着他到了飞机尾部
so you followed him to the back of the plane
然后你杀了他
and you killed him.
杀了他  你什么意思
Killed him? What do you mean?
我们就在那里发现他的
We found him right over there.
不不不  其实是
No. No, no, no, no, no! No, no! In fact,
几秒钟后  这个人接到了许多短信
seconds after that, this man got numerous texts on his phone
然后他开始回信息  然后他就跑开了
and then began texting back, and then he rushed off.
那是我最后一次见他
Look, this is the last I saw of him.
他的手机在我们这  哈达德
We have his phone, Haddad.
他只发了一条短信
He only sent one text.
不  我知道自己看见了什么
No, I know what I saw.
他接到了一堆短信  至少有五条
He got a bunch of texts, five at least.
爸爸
Dad?
能出来一下吗
Could I see you for a second?
有发现吗
Anything?
我们查看了他的行李
We checked his luggage.
没有枪  没有炸弹
No gun, no device,
没有任何证明他是恐怖分子的东西
nothing that speaks to terrorism.
政府无法证实他母亲生病的说辞
Look, state can't confirm the story about the sick mother,
但哈达德的部分说辞被证实了
but part of Haddad's story checks out.
原来那个空警福特
Turns out that air marshal Ford
在飞机上还有另一部手机
had a second phone on the flight.
是他的私人电话
It was his personal cell.
尸体上没找到另一部手机
Well, we didn't find a second phone on the body.
如果上面有证据  很可能
Well, if it had evidence on it, it's possible
已经被凶手拿走了
the killer removed it.
没有手机的情况下可以调取他的短信吗
Can we recover his texts without the phone?
可以  不过需要花费些时间
Yeah, but it's gonna take some time
才能让手机公司发给我们
to get the phone company to release them.
可现在我们没那么多时间
And time is something we don't have.
这些事没法洗清哈达德的嫌疑
And none of this clears Haddad.
这些可能都是障眼法
This could all be a smokescreen.
让我们去追踪一些虚无的线索
Something for us to chase
从而掩盖他真实的计划
while his real plan unfolds.
我们需要那部手机
We need that phone.
如果福特在发短信的话  他一定连接了
If Ford was texting, he must have been connected
飞机上的无线网络
to the plane's WiFi.
也就是说那部手机可能还在联网
Which means the phone may still be connected.
好  那托瑞能不能用
Right. So can Tory ping his cell
"找到我的用户"那个应用  让手机响
using the "Find my users" App, make it beep?
好了  我进去了
Okay, I'm in.
我已经把他的号码连接到应用上了
I've linked his number into the app.
等你准备好就发出信号
Ready to ping when you are.
好  就位了
Okay, stand by.
好了  大家都准备好了吗
All right, everyone ready?
准备好了  法拉和我在二等舱
Ready. Farrah and I are in coach,
吉姆在头等舱
and Jim is in first class.
注意看有没有人看手机
Watch for anyone reaching for their phone.
福特的手机可能就在凶手的手里
Ford's phone could be in the killer's hands.
好的
Okay.
行动
Go.
信号发出
Pinging now.
在那里
Over there.
错误警报
False alarm.
你听见什么声音了吗
Do you hear anything?
如果有人取出电池
If someone removed the battery
或者关机  托瑞就没法...
or even turned it off, Tory's not gonna be able --
我有发现
I have something.
在哪
Where is it?
见鬼
Oh, crap.
我讨厌蛇
I hate snakes.
-一条蛇需要多久才能...  -在那里
- How long does it take a snake to pass a -- - There it is.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god. Okay.
手机锁了  我们需要解锁密码
It's locked. We need his pass code.
或者他的指纹
Or his fingerprint.
真的非常抱歉
I am...so sorry about this,
感谢你为国家做出的贡献
and thank you for your service to our country.
好了
Okay.
上面说了什么
What's it say?
上面有很多短信
It's got at least a dozen texts on here.
你看吧  我告诉过你
You see? I told you.
-帅哥  想找点乐子吗  -你是谁
- "Hey, sexy, wanna have some fun?" - "Who is this?"
到后面来找我你就知道了
"Meet me in the back of the plane and find out."
但他们不愿意表明身份
But then when they refuse to reveal their identity,
福特不愿意见面
Ford won't meet.
看  短信开始有敌意了
Look. The texts start to get hostile.
照我说的做  否则你就麻烦了
"Do what I say, or you'll have a situation on your hands."
-什么麻烦  -就是雇你来阻止的麻烦
- "What kind of situation?" - "The kind you're hired to prevent."
威胁飞机安全是联邦刑事犯罪
"It's a federal offense to threaten an aircraft."
如果我坚持到底
"It's not a threat if I follow through
并且让飞机坠毁  就不是威胁了
and take down this plane."
幕后黑手不管是谁  还在飞机上
Whoever's behind this is still on the plane.
-贝克特  我有线索了  -别挂电话
- Beckett, I've got something. Yeah, hold on.
空警手机上的短信
Those texts on the Marshal's phone, they were sent
是一部预付费手机发来的
from a pre-paid cell.
你能查到吗
Can you trace it?
不能  手机好像关机了
No, it looks like it's been turned off.
查一下手机号  看能不能找到
Okay, run down that number. See if you can find out
是谁在哪里买到的  卡塞尔
who bought it and from where. Castle?
-你还在吗  -是的  我在
- You still there? - Yeah, I'm here.
幕后黑手肯定有所准备
Whoever's behind this did their homework.
他们有福特的私人电话
They had Ford's personal number
也知道如何操控他
and they knew exactly how to manipulate him.
他们肯定认识他
They must have known him somehow.
我已经让他们去查福特的一切
I've got the boys digging into Ford's life --
财物  行踪  电话记录
Financials, movements, phone records.
他们在找线索看能不能把他和
They're looking for anything that'll connect him
这架航班上的什么人联系起来
to someone on that flight.
好的  让他们查快一点
Well, tell them to dig a little faster
在发短信的人把威胁变成现实之前
before our texter makes good on his threat to take us down.
卡塞尔  我
Castle, I...
我知道  我也是
I know. Me, too.
有线索了就给我打电话
Call me when you have something.
好的
Okay.
我们不能干坐着等分局的消息
We can't just sit around and wait for word from the precinct.
肯定有什么是我们能做的
There has to be something we can do.
也许真的有
Well, maybe there is.
只有百分之十的人是左撇子
Only 10% of the population is left-handed.
我们肯定有法子能找出乘客当中
There must be a way for us to figure out who of the passengers
谁是左撇子  这样能缩小嫌疑人的范围
is a southpaw, thus narrowing our suspect pool.
我们可以把入境和海关申报表发下去
We could pass out customs and immigration forms.
这样我们就知道谁是左撇子了
Then we'd know who's left-handed.
聪明  现在你的思维方式就像个推理作家
Brilliant. Now you're thinking like a mystery writer.
-你觉得这有用吗  -不知道
- Think this will work? - I don't know.
总比什么都不做好
It's better than doing nothing.
没能像那样睡过去简直太遗憾了
Too bad we didn't sleep through this, too, huh?
只是确认一下它还在
Just making sure it's still there.
贝克特  我找到了
Beckett, I got it.
给空警发短信的手机
The phone that texted the Marshal --
手机是在网上购买并且是在机场
The phone was purchased online and picked up at the airport
一个空运商店提货的
at a flight tech express store
就在航班起飞前半小时不到
Less than half an hour before the flight.
那家商店有摄像头吗
Does the store have any cameras?
没有  机场的摄像头
No, and the cameras in the airport
都没有很好的角度能够拍到收银处
don't have a good angle on the register.
但我们不需要监控视频
But we don't need video.
买主用的是信用卡
The purchaser used a credit card.
我们找到了她的名字  我查了旅客名单
We have her name, and I checked the manifest.
她就在飞机上
She's on the plane.
马琳·辛格
Marilyn Singer?
她说是大洋航空的前执行总监
Yeah, she's a former Oceanic executive
去年被解雇  卡塞尔听这个
who got fired last year, and, Castle, get this.
她对航空公司提出非法解雇的诉讼
She filed a wrongful termination suit accusing the airline
指控公司排挤她
of blackballing her, and last week the judge
上周法官判她败诉
ruled against her in favor of Oceanic Airlines.
于是她想
So she wants to --
想让他们的飞机坠毁
So she wants to take down
来进行报复吗
one of their planes for revenge?
听上去有点极端
That seems a little extreme.
是的  卡塞尔  但这和她发给空警
Yes, Castle, but it's consistent with the texts
短信的内容一致
she sent the air marshal.
对她来说  毁掉坑了她的航空公司
and what better way for her to destroy the airline
还有什么更好的办法吗
she believes ruined her life?
她坐在什么位置
What seat is she in?
那是马琳吗
That's Marilyn?
假发  眼镜
The hair, the glasses --
她不想被人认出来
She did not want to be recognized.
爸爸  左手  就是她
Dad, left hand. It's her.
我们需要在她实施计划之前
Okay, we need to isolate her before she carries out
-把她隔离起来  -怎么做呢
- whatever her plan is. - How?
回到你的座位
Go to your seat.
你要做什么
What are you gonna do?
非常蠢的事
Something very stupid.
她有枪
She has a gun.
所以我让你离得远一点
Which is why I want you as far away as possible.
可我也担心你啊
You know I feel the same way about you, right?
我知道  听着
I do, I do. Now...
回到你的座位  求你了
Go back to your seat. Please.
我需要一杯酒
I'm gonna need a glass of wine.
红酒
Red.
天啊  太对不起了
Oh, my -- I am so sorry.
很抱歉  女士
My apologies, ma'am.
厨房有去污剂
I have stain remover in the galley.
跟我来  我们会帮你弄干净
Come with me. We'll clean you up.
谢谢  不用  我包里有清洁湿巾
Thank you, no, I've got detergent wipes in my bag.
女士  会留下污渍的
Ma'am, you don't want that to set.
跟我到后面  我们会处理好的
Come back with me, and we'll take care of it.
别碰我  我没事
Don't touch me. I'm fine.
-你还是跟她走吧  -我说了我没事
- Maybe you should go with her. - I said I'm fine.
有枪
Gun!
我的天
Oh, my god!
女士们先生们  请坐好
Uh...ladies and gentlemen, please remain seated.
我们显然遇到了些情况  但一切都在掌控中
We obviously had a situation, but we have it under control.
我告诉你  这是个误会
I'm telling you, this is some kind of mistake.
那枪不是我的
That gun is not mine.
马琳你有什么计划
What was your plan, Marilyn?
挟持人质  让飞机坠毁吗
Take hostages, try to bring down the plane?
让飞机坠机
Bring down the plane?
你在乱说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我说的是你指控大洋航空败诉
I'm talking about the suit you lost against Oceanic,
以及你发到这个手机上的威胁短信
and the threatening texts you sent from this phone.
那不是我的手机
That is not my phone.
在你包里  用你的信用卡买的
It was in your purse, paid for with your credit card.
凯尔在哪  我要和他谈
Where's Kyle? I want to talk to Kyle.
我知道他是这架航班的空警
I know he's the air marshal on this flight.
是他让你这么做的吗  这一点都不好笑
Did he put you up to this? Because it is not funny.
你怎么会认识福特先生
How is it that you know Mr. Ford?
他是我男朋友  行了吧
He's my boyfriend, all right?
如果他觉得这是在教训我
And if he thinks he's teaching me a lesson,
我要真的发火了
I'm going to be seriously pissed.
他现在在哪
Now where is he?
马琳
Marilyn...
凯尔死了
Kyle is dead.
死了
Dead?
凯尔死了  怎么会这样
Kyle's dead? How?
这你应该清楚
You should know.
他的枪就在你包里
His gun was in your purse.
不是  我
No. I --
我根本不知道发生了什么事
I-I don't understand what's going on.
一定是有人在我去洗手间的时候
Someone else must have put that in my bag with the phone
把枪和手机放进我的包里
when I was in the bathroom.
你出门旅行总是戴假发吗
And I suppose you always wear a wig when you travel?
你不懂  我以为
You don't understand. I thought --
我以为凯尔有外遇了
I thought kyle was having an affair.
这本是我们拍拖半周年纪念日
It was our 6-month anniversary,
我们本来要一起过周末的
and we were supposed to go away for the weekend.
但最后一刻  凯尔打电话给我
But at the last minute, Kyle called
说他得在这班飞机上工作
and said he had to work this flight,
他要顶替某人的班
that he had to fill in for someone.
但我听出了言外之意
But there was something in his voice,
好像他没有告诉我实情
like he wasn't telling me the whole story.
所以你决定跟踪他  跟他上同一班飞机
So you decided to stalk him, follow him onto this plane?
我们在空中邂逅
We met in the air.
在长途跋涉中坠入爱河
Fell in love on the long haul.
我想也许他爱上了其他人
I thought maybe he'd found someone else.
所以你就引他来到这  和他对质
Is that why you lured him back here? To confront him?
事情愈演愈烈  你一气之下杀了他
And when it all went south, you killed him in a rage?
不是
No.
我不会这么做的  拜托
I wouldn't do that. Please.
你们一定要相信我
You have to believe me.
我没法相信
I can't afford to.
吉姆  把她带到下面去  确保她别乱跑
Jim, take her down below. Make sure she's secure.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道  就是
I don't know. Just --
当我告诉她福特死了的时候
When I told her Ford was dead,
她的反应看起来如此真实
her reaction seemed so real.
爸爸  枪和手机都在她的包里
Dad, the gun and phone were in her purse.
她又是左撇子  我
She's left-handed. I --
不  我知道  所有的证据都指向她
No, I know, I know. Everything fits.
但为什么网购
But why buy a pre-paid phone online
然后很快就去机场店里取
just to pick it up at the airport store minutes later?
何不直接去店里买
Why not just walk into the store and buy it?
还有为什么要用会被追踪到的
And why use a credit card that could be traced
信用卡  除非
back to her, unless...
除非这都是计划好的
Unless that was part of the plan?
证据都指向完美的嫌疑人
To give us the perfect suspect
这样我们就不会追查真相了
so we'd stop looking for the truth.
你觉得有人陷害她
You think someone set her up?
我觉得这件事没这么简单
I think something else is going on here.
卡塞尔  你在飞机上经历了很多
Look, Castle, you've been through a lot up there,
也许是你作家想象力太丰富
so maybe your storyteller's imagination's
-又开始乱推理了  -我跟你说
- getting the best of you. - I'm telling you,
这件事没那么简单
there's a lot more going on here.
有人想要我们就此结案  但并没有
Someone wants us to think this is over, but it's not.
卡塞尔也许是对的
Castle may be right.
我们联系了空警局
We contacted the Air Marshal Service.
福特没有帮人顶替
Ford wasn't filling in for anyone.
是他要求上这班飞机的
He requested to be on that flight.
我们复查了福特的财务记录
We also double-checked Ford's financial records,
发现刚刚有一笔交易
and we found a transaction that just posted.
是一笔9950美元电汇到他的银行账户
It turns out $9,950 was wired to his bank account
就在飞机起飞前几分钟
just minutes before takeoff.
刚好在一万美元以下
Just under the $10,000 mark.
有人不想让联调局知道
Someone didn't want to tip off the Feds.
不管发生了什么事  福特都牵涉其中
Whatever's going on up there, Ford is involved.
这钱是从哪来的
Who's the money from?
这个人  维克托·科斯托夫·迪特里希
This guy -- Victor Kristoph Dietrich.
他是个富有的德国实业家
He's a wealthy German industrialist,
在进出口贸易圈名气很大
big name in the import/export business.
美国海关人员指出他涉嫌
U.S. Customs officials have flagged him
多次违规  但从未被逮到
several times for violations, but nothing ever stuck.
你觉得福特要求上这个航班
Do you think Ford requested to be on this flight
是因为迪特里希花钱雇他
because Dietrich paid him to be on it?
是的  但原因呢
Yes, but why?
迪特里希现在在哪
Where is Dietrich?
他的办公室离这两个街区
His office is two blocks away.
-马上叫来问话  -好的
-I want him here. - Now. Yeah.
我很抱歉  警探  但我从没见过这个人
I am sorry, Detectives, but I've never seen him before.
那为何你的账户转了一万美元
Then why was $10,000 transferred from your bank account
到他的账户  迪特里希先生
to his, Mr. Dietrich?
-一定是银行失误吧  -不  不是
- Must be some kind of banking error. - No, it's not.
两边的银行都确认过了
Both of your financial institutions confirmed it.
乐善好施又不算犯罪
It isn't a crime to give a gift.
怎么  这是礼物吗
Oh, so it's a gift now?
给一个你素昧平生的人
To someone that you don't even know?
你为何要付钱
What were you paying
给福特空警  迪特里希先生
the Air Marshal for, Mr. Dietrich?
很高兴和你们谈话  但我得走了
This has been delightful, but I'm afraid I have to go.
不行  你哪都不能去
Um, no. You're -- you're not going anywhere.
你没有理由扣押我
You have no cause to hold me.
事实上  我们有
Actually, we do.
作为重要证人
As a material witness.
什么案子的证人
Witness to what?
在跨大西洋航班上
The murder of a Federal Air Marshal
谋杀联邦空警
On a transatlantic flight.
谋杀
Murder?
福特空警  死了
Air Marshal Ford is -- is dead?
是的  这些钱是用来做什么的
Yes. Now what was the money for?
安保
Security.
什么样的安保
What kind of security?
我和布兰斯顿拍卖行商量
I consult with Brampton's auction house.
雇佣了福特提供保护
I hired Mr. Ford to provide protection
我们要求他保护那架飞机上
for a piece we acquired from the met that was
运送的一件东西
being transported on that plane.
什么样的东西
What kind of a piece?
是装饰艺术派
It is an Art Deco Era
路易·卡莱天神价值1330万的手表
Louis Callay Celestialis watch worth $13.3 million.
手表在福特手上
And ford was carrying it?
他只是负责看着手表
He was merely keeping an eye on it.
我们的一个内部学徒
One of our in-house apprentices
戴着那块表
Is actually wearing the timepiece.
你让一个学徒戴着1300万的手表
You gave an apprentice a $13 million watch?
是的  这是拍卖行很常见的做法
Yeah, it's a common auction house practice.
派一个雇员飞到海外
They fly an employee to a foreign country
戴着物品这样就不用索赔
wearing the goods so that they don't have to claim it
或者交税了
or pay taxes on it.
这件东西价值不菲
With such a valuable piece,
我想要一个真正的保安跟着飞
I wanted real security for the flight,
福特协助我保护递送人
and Ford was backing up my courier.
-仅此而已  -远不止于此
- That was all. - Except that wasn't all.
-事情出了岔子  -是的
- Something went awry. - Yes.
递送人在起飞后不久
The courier stopped replying to my texts
便没有回复我的短信
shortly after takeoff.
递送人的名字叫什么  坐在哪个位子
What was the courier's name, and where was he sitting?
艾伦·里奇  艾伦  醒醒
Aaron Rich? Aaron, wake up.
他被下药了  醒醒
I think he's been drugged. Wake up.
-卡塞尔先生  你在干什么  -调查案子
- Mr. Castle, what are you doing? - It's part of the investigation.
-犯罪嫌疑人已被逮捕  -或许并没有
- The suspect is in custody. - Maybe not.
不不不
No. No. No, no, no, no.
我不该睡着的
I wasn't supposed to fall asleep.
感谢上帝
Thank god.
放开我
Let go of me!
先别感谢上帝
Don't thank god just yet.
这表是假的
This watch is a fake.
真的天神表是自动上发条的
The real celestialis is self-winding.
这表有旋钮
This watch has a knob.
也就是说这一切跟恐怖主义无关
Which means this was never about terrorism,
这是劫案
it was about a heist.
我不明白
I don't -- I don't understand.
你戴的是假冒的
You're wearing a knockoff.
睡着时被调包了
It got switched out while you were sleeping.
你在下飞机之后
You weren't supposed to realize it
才会发觉
until you were off the plane
到时真表早就不见踪影了
and the real watch was long gone.
那个讨厌的家伙坐位被调换了
That obnoxious guy who had his seat changed.
他原本应该坐在这里吗
Was this originally where he was supposed to sit?
是的  但福特先生两天前要求坐这里
Yes, but Mr. Ford put in a request for that seat
空警是有优先权的
two days ago, and air marshals get priority,
于是就把坐位留给了他
so the system assigned it to him.
他知道坐这里是看管手表
He knew it was the perfect vantage point
的最佳位置
from which to watch the watch.
但小偷一定是发现了
But the thief must have found out.
有空警坐在这  小偷没法动手
And they couldn't steal the watch with an air marshal
于是就把他从头等舱引走
sitting right there, so they had to lure ford out of first class.
用一部能追查到
Using a phone that, if traced,
福特女友的手机
would lead them back to Ford's girlfriend,
她刚好有作案动机
who had a motive.
老爸  这意味着小偷知道谁在飞机上
Dad, that means the thief knows who's on the plane.
能拿到旅客名单  位置表
They had access to the manifest, seat assignments,
还了解福特的私人生活
Ford's personal life.
还有旅客的信用卡
And passenger credit cards.
这是内部人干的
This was an inside job.
艾伦  饮品是谁给你的
Aaron, who served you this drink?
有人下了药
Because someone spiked it.
不记得
I can't remember.
但通常是她
But it's usually her.
不是我  我没给人下药
No. No. I did not drug anybody.
爸  她做不到
Dad, she couldn't have.
她当时在第二过道给我们服务
She was serving us over in aisle 2.
那就是...
Well, then it was...
退后
Stay back.
黛比
Debbie?
是你
You?
为什么
Why?
30年  法拉
30 years, Farrah.
30年
30 years
忠诚服务
of loyal service.
我终于要退休了
I was finally ready to retire.
大洋航空做了什么
So what does Oceanic do?
他们调整
They restructure...
废除了我们的养老保险
and eliminate our peions.
黛比
Debbie...
这不是你想做的事  放下枪
You don't want to do this. Drop this gun.
你知道每个月在头等舱
Do you have any idea what it's like
给这个混小子服务什么感受吗
serving this little punk kid in first class every month?
听他吹嘘手腕上的东西
Hearing him brag about how much money
价值连城
he's got strapped to his wrist.
而我一无所有
When I have nothing.
于是当你得知他又要坐这架航班
So when you found out he was taking this flight again,
决定有所行动
you decided to do something.
我听说了那块表
I heard about that watch.
要被拍卖
How it was gonna be auctioned off.
1300万美金
That's $13 million!
但没人
But nobody...
没人会受到伤害的
Nobody was supposed to get hurt.
我只需福特离开他
All right, I j-- I just needed Ford to step away
一小会儿
from him for like a minute.
但当他看到艾伦睡着了
But when he saw Aaron was sleeping...
他就明白了
He knew.
他在货舱找到我
He tracked me down to the cargo hold.
黛比
Debbie...
航空公司对你所作所为
What the airline did to you
不公平
was unfair.
别求你别把事情搞得更糟
But please don't make it worse.
你不是这样的人
This isn't who you are.
不是
It's not. It's not.
我们即将着落
We'll be landing soon.
请回到你的座位
You can go ahead and re-take your seat...
我们深表抱歉
with our apologies.
感谢你相信我  卡塞尔先生
Thank you for believing me, Mr. Castle,
也感谢你将杀害凯尔的凶手逮捕
and for bringing Kyle's killer to justice.
凯尔被害  请节哀
I'm -- I'm very sorry for your loss.
哈达德先生
Mr. Haddad.
不幸的是  飞机一降落
Unfortunately, when the plane lands,
你将因使用偷窃护照旅行
you are going to be detained
而被逮捕
for traveling on a stolen passport.
但我让纽约的朋友联系了当局
However, I had my friends in New York make some calls.
如果你的说辞被证实
If your story checks out,
他们会在你被起诉前
the authorities here are going to allow you
回到叙利亚
to travel to Syria to see your family
和家人团聚
before you face charges.
谢谢你  卡塞尔先生
Thank you, Mr. Castle.
保重
Be safe.
而你
And you.
今天你的表现让我很骄傲
I am very proud of the way you handled yourself today.
你对黛比所说的话...
What you said to Debbie, it was...
非常勇敢
very brave.
感谢夸奖
Thanks.
和朋友的小聚我打算延后
You know, I think I'm going to postpone my pub date.
是吗
You are?
你不是不想和我黏在一起吗
I thought you said you didn't want to be attached at the hip.
在今天经历的一切后
Yeah. Well, after what happened today,
-黏在一起挺好  -我也这样想
- I kind of do. - Me, too.
乘客们  我是机长
Folks, this is your Captain.
我们即将抵达伦敦希思罗机场
We're starting our final descent into London Heathrow.
请回到自己的座位
Please take your seats.
我们马上着陆
We'll have you on the ground shortly.